Trinity and Beyond: The Atomic Bomb Movie is a documentary,
history, war film directed by Peter Kuran.
"Trinity and Beyond" is an unsettling yet visually fascinating documentary presenting
the history of nuclear weapons development and testing between 1945-1963.
Narrated by William Shatner and featuring an original score performed by the Moscow Symphony Orchestra, this
award-winning documentary reveals previously unreleased and classified government footage from several countries.
Narrator, played by William Shatner.
Self - Nuclear Physicist, played by Edward Teller.
Self - Commander Joint Task Force One (archive
footage), played by W.H.P. Blandy.
Self - Nuclear Weaponeer, played by Frank H. Shelton.
Self - U.S. President (archive footage), played by Dwight D. Eisenhower.
Self - U.S Ambassador (1961-1965) to the UN (archive
footage), played by Adlai Stevenson.
Trinity and Beyond: The Atomic Bomb Movie is a 1995 American documentary
film directed by Peter Kuran and narrated by William Shatner.
Using restored archive footage, the film traces the development of nuclear weapons and their testing, from
America's Trinity test of 1945 (hence the title) to the first Chinese atomic bomb test in 1964.
Kuran's commentary on the DVD version claims that the DVD replaces some
of the original footage with better-quality versions.
There are some short special effects sequences too.
The film has also since been released on Blu-ray.
The film explores themes of atomic bomb,
energiestrahlenwaffe, atomic bomb test, nuclear explosion.